slowfoodusa.org 2013-06-29

# About Us : Slow Food USA

### PRIVACY PRINCIPLES

###  This Web site is owned and operated by Slow Food USA. Our intention is to provide an informative tool for those interested in conservation and as a means of allowing our constituency to become more involved in our mission. We recognize that visitors to our site may be concerned about the information they provide to us and how we treat that information. Slow Food USA is committed to honoring our constituents’ privacy preferences. To this end, Slow Food USA supports the following principles: 

## CONSUMER CHOICE

We believe a visitor to our site is the one to best determine:

  * When—and under what conditions—to provide “personally identifiable information” (e.g. data that may be used to identify, contact, or locate a person).

  * When such information may be shared with other organizations.

  * When to remain anonymous.

## Informed Consent

If personally identifiable information is collected, we believe a visitor to our site has the right to:

  * Know when we are collecting personal information.

  * Know what personal information is collected, and the purpose of collection.

  * Expect the opportunity to choose whether or not personal information will be provided to any third parties.

  * Expect reasonable steps to be taken to protect personal information from unauthorized use.

  * Review the accuracy of personal information and update it.

### PRIVACY POLICY

This policy covers Web sites owned or operated by Slow Food USA. We encourage you to take the time to read this privacy policy.

## Personal Information Collected

In general, when you visit our Web sites and access information you remain anonymous. We do not require you to register or provide personal information to us to view our site. There are occasions when we will ask for additional information. We do this to better understand and respond to your needs, and provide you with services that may be valuable to you. For example, personally identifiable information will be collected in order for you to become a member of Slow Food USA online.

## Use of Information

Personally identifiable information is not made available to other non-profit organizations or to for-profit organizations unless you request otherwise. We will not provide any of your personal information to other organizations.

## Security of Your Credit Card Information

We will take appropriate steps to protect your privacy. We will also protect your personal information in storage. For example, if you supply us with your credit card information to become a member or make a donation, we encrypt the card number. Contributions may also be made by printing out the online form and mailing it to:

Attn: Member Services  
Slow Food USA  
68 Summit Street, 2B  
Brooklyn, NY 11231

You can also contact us at [membership@slowfoodusa.org](mailto:membership@slowfoodusa.org) or call us between 9:30 a.m. and 5:30 p.m. EST at 718.260.8000.

## Links to Third Party Sites

We provide links to third party sites. Since we do not control those Web sites, we encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these third party sites.

## Cookies

_What are “Cookies”?_ “Cookies” are small files sent from a Web server to your computer through your browser program. There are two types of cookies: non-persistent and persistent cookies.

A non-persistent cookie enables a Web site to temporarily keep information on your computer as you travel from one page to another on our site. This cookie is automatically deleted from your machine when you close your browser. Because these cookies are necessary to provide some functions, failure to allow such cookies may make some of the functions on our Web site unavailable to you.

A persistent cookie is kept even when you close your browser. You can manually delete these cookies using commands specific to your browser and computer system. These cookies store information that would generally not change from session to session. They also contain information that would need to be reentered by you each time you visit the Web site. For example, a common use of persistent cookies is to allow a registered site visitor to enter the site without having to specify their user-id and password.

_Use of Cookies:_ Slow Food USA uses cookies for various reasons. Slow Food USA only reads cookies written by our site. It does not use cookies to obtain information on other Web sites that you may visit. We may use cookies to store some history about the parts of our sites that you have visited to help you navigate our site more easily or to alert you to related pages on our site that may interest you.

## Electronic Mail sent to us containing personal information

You may decide to send Slow Food USA personally identifying information, for example, in a message containing information about your membership. We will only use this information to identify you as a member of Slow Food USA and to determine how to respond to the electronic mail. We will not use this information for any purpose other than to resolve the matter identified in the email.

## Questions

Slow Food USA welcomes comments and questions on this policy. We are dedicated to protecting your personal information, and will make every reasonable effort to keep that information secure.

If you have any questions, please contact us at [info@slowfoodusa.org](mailto:info@slowfoodusa.org) or call us between 9:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. EST at 718.260.8000..

You can help Slow Food USA maintain the accuracy of your information by notifying us of any changes to your address, title, phone number or email address. To update your membership file, email us at [info@slowfoodusa.org](mailto:info@slowfoodusa.org) , or write us at:

Attn: Member Services  
Slow Food USA  
68 Summit Street, 2B  
Brooklyn, NY 11231

## Terms and Conditions: User Conduct

You agree to abide by all applicable local, state, national and international laws and regulations regarding your use of our service.

## Credit Card

You agree that you are an authorized user of any credit card that you supply to us, and you understand and agree that we have an obligation to fully investigate any possible fraudulent credit card use. If you are under 18 years of age, you must have parental consent in order to purchase tickets and participate in Slow Food USA.

## Refund Policy

Slow Food USA will issue refunds at our sole discretion. Requests for refunds must be made in the following manner to be considered:  
The refund request has to be in writing via letter; and that the customer shall have paid for by Visa or MasterCard or debit card via our website.  
Refund Procedures  
    The letter should be sent to:  
    Attn: Member Services  
    Slow Food USA  
    68 Summit Street, 2B  
    Brooklyn, NY 11231

Information Required in the letter:  
    Contact person’s name  
    Copy of contact person’s ID  
    Contact person’s local phone number and address  
    Person’s local bank account number for refund, name of the bank and account holder’s name  
    Money order or postal note number or copy of the slip  
    Date and method of the purchase  
Standard turnaround time for refund is within one month from the date we receive the customer refund request letter. We will notify the customer of its decision to refund or to reject the refund request for the reasons stated in this policy within one month from the date we receive the customer refund request letter.

## Payment Page

The security of your personal information is very important to us, and we are committed to protecting the information we collect. While we cannot guarantee absolute security of your personal information, [http://www.slowfoodusa.org](http://www.slowfoodusa.org/) uses firewalls and Secure Socket Layers for all personal data we collect from you. We also employ many different security techniques to protect personal data against loss, misuse, alteration, and unauthorized access.

The information you provide to us will also be covered by this policy.  
Due to the rapidly evolving technologies on the Internet, we may occasionally update this policy. All revisions will be posted to this site. A revised Privacy Policy will apply only to data collected subsequent to its effective date.
